<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Tommi Mäkelä</title>
    <link>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Tommi Mäkelä</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Bank Customer Churn Classification</title>
      <link>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview This project builds a machine learning model to predict customer churn in the banking sector. Using customer demographics, account information, and financial data, the model identifies customers at risk of leaving the bank.
The solution is implemented end-to-end on Snowflake, leveraging Snowflake ML for feature engineering, model training, deployment, and inference. This approach enables a scalable, secure, and production-ready churn prediction system aligned with real-world banking requirements.
The final model uses an XGBoost Classifier, achieving an accuracy of 87%, and is managed through Snowflake’s built-in model registry for versioning and governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Store Sales Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 21:54:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>The project, implemented using Python, forecasts store sales using historical unit sales data for thousands of items across multiple stores. Preprocessing involved handling missing values, encoding categories, and extracting date features, ensuring proper time-series formatting. Feature engineering included lag features, rolling stats, store-item patterns, and Ecuador national and local holidays, along with temporal patterns like trends and seasonality. ML models: The first used Linear Regression (scikit-learn) for baseline predictions, followed by Deep Learning (LSTM networks with TensorFlow) to improve accuracy by capturing complex temporal patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project X: Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>🚧 This is a placeholder for an upcoming project. 🚧
I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on a new Data Science project that will be featured here soon. This section will showcase the problem, approach, tools used, and key results — just like my other projects.
In the meantime, feel free to explore the other projects in my portfolio or check out my GitHub for recent activity.
Stay tuned!
Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TommMakk.github.io/projects-portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tommi-ma/   GitHub: https://github.com/TommMakk    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>